Guide to the Herndon Dowling Herpetological Collection MS 059
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- General Files
  - Research - Background
    - Geography Eastern Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_40)
      bay 10, drawer 1
      zoogeography-snakes, herp zoogeography, zoogeography non-snakes, geography, palearctic, PA North Africa, PE British Isles, PE France, PE Germany, PE Greece, PE Italy, Mediterranian Islands, Poland, Portugal, Russia, Spain, Mideast.
    - Geography Eastern Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_41)
      oriental palearctica, China, Japan, Hong Kong, Korea, Siberia, Ryukyu Isalnds, Ethiopian, Indian Ocean, Comoro Islands, Madagascar, Mauritis, Oriental
    - Geography Eastern Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_42)
      Bangladesh, Burma, Boulenger GA, Burma: vipers and venoms, Laos, Malaysia, Nepal
    - Geography Eastern Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_43)
      bay 10, drawer 3
      Pakistan, Vietnam, East Indies, O EI Bomeo, OEI Indonesia, OEI Phillipines, Australia, Pacific Ocean, SP Fiji, SP Hawaii, SP New Caledonia, SP New Zealand, SP Solomon Islands.
    - Geography Eastern Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_44)
      bay 11, drawer 3
      Plant geography, T Neotropic, maps: Central America, neotropical snakes, T CA Central America, Belize, Costa Rica, Guatemala, Honduras, Nicuragua, Panama, El Salvador, West Indies, South America.
    - Geography Western Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_45)
      Carribean history, West Indian snakes, Bahamas, Barbados, Cayman, Cuba, Dominica, Grenada, Hispaniola, Jamaica, Martinique, Puerto Rico, St. Luca, Tobago, Trinidad, Argentina, Bolina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia.
    - Geography Eastern Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_46)
      Nevada de Santa Maria, Galapagos, French Guinea, Surinam, Uruguay, Venezuela, Nearctic, Mexico.
    - Geography Western Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_47)
      United States, Alabama, Arkansas, Arizona, California, Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Florida, Georgia.
    - Geography Western Hemisphere, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_48)
      Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Louisiana, Maryland, Michigan, Mississippi, Missouri, Nebraska, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Virginia, Wyoming, Canada.
    - Vertebrate Natural History Galapagos, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_49)
      bay 10, drawer 2
      Natural History Vertebrae-exams, schedule, diversity, earth history, lab manual, introduction, organisms.
    - Vertebrate Natural History Galapagos, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_50)
      Reptiles, birds, fishes, amphibians.
    - Vertebrate Natural History Galapagos, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_51)
      Galapagos 1964-letters and station program Amphibians reading list
    - Vertebrate Natural History Galapagos, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_52)
      Animal dealers, herp dealers, live animal and specimen dealers.
    - Taxonomy Biochemistry, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_53)
      Snakes: common names, classification: prindiphles, principles of systemmics, taxonomy non-snake, original descriptions:genera:amphibia, non-snake checklists, international commision, type lists, dinosaurs and birds, evolution-snakes, snake classification, systematics and tax: snake.
    - Taxonomy Biochemistry, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_54)
      general concepts, serology, evolution (non-snakes), phylogeny, cladograms, computer programs, Elisa, immunology, Domergue CA, George DW, Lawson R, Immunology, Minton SA.
    - Taxonomy Biochemistry, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_55)
      bay 10, drawer 3.
      Immunology technique, genomic, molecular evolution, molecular-snakes, molecular-non snakes, electrophoresis, snakes and tissues (runs).
    - Taxonomy Biochemistry, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_56)
      Elisa, AID, serology-non snake, biochemical techniques, gels and buffers, electrophoresis, molecular studies, DNA, RNA, ribosomal RNA.
    - MS Elaphe Obsoleta 2002, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_63)
      bay 12, drawer 1
      Taxonomic methods, fossils and history, molecular and genetics, natural history notes, E.obsoleta specimen lists, obsoleta group, original descriptions, Elaphe: Nearctic: E. Obsoleta taxonomic, Elaphe Bairdi, EO General papers.
    - MS Elaphe Obsoleta 2002, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_64)
      Lawson Robin, EO Florida, EO AL, Miss, KY, Ten, SC, NC, Georgia, Texas, LA, AR, OK Elaphe Bairdi
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_077)
      loose.
      Snake types, generic index, species classifications, literature bibliogrpahy.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_078)
      Indexes, snake parts.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_079)
      copies of articles and published papers.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_080)
      Photocopies of articles and notes. Contains Prodromus of new classification of snakes manuscript draft.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_81)
      photo copies and notes MS, authorships and references, serpents world, information for/correspondence with book publishers.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_82)
      Photocopies and notes, snake types and evolution, snake classification, primative snake phylogony.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_83)
      Bay 12, drawer 2.
      printed materials snake types.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_83)
      snake types.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_84)
      bay 12, drawer 2.
      snake related groups and publications, research and notes.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_85)
      bay 12, drawer 3.
      Locations, correspondence, field notes.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_86)
      bay 12 drawer 3.
      snake evolution.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_87)
      bay 12, drawer 4.
      snake evolution, microfilm punch cards.
  - Published materials and manuscripts, circa 1960-2000
    Recent Reprints - originally Bay 2, drawer 3; Manuscripts of published papers - originally Bay 2, drawer 4; Dowling reprints - originally Bay 3, drawer 3. This material is unprocessed.
    - Recent Reprints, 1987-2004 (Box ms059_files_04)
      bay 2, drawer 3
      Appears to be reprints of Dowling's work, 1987-2004
    - Manuscripts of Published Papers, 1980-1993 (Box ms059_files_05)
      bay 2, drawer 4
      Notes and drafts of Xenodermatid snakes in America. Includes multiple reprints of "Reply to Collins"
    - Serpent World, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_65)
      bay 12, drawer 2
      Serpent world I outline, the serpent world, new class maps, snake book 1968, serprents world: origin and evolution
    - Serpent World, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_66)
      prodromus 1997 neotropics, neotropics zoogeography, completed copy NA SNA.
    - Serpent World, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_67)
      Ethiopian Pix, madagascan snakes, African radiation, African revisit, chpt 13: the Australian region, Australia maps, Elapoidea, Elapidae.
    - Serpent World, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_68)
      higher categories in herpatology, serpents manuscript: preface, structure and function, life history, faunas, index, classification
      Silver-burduett, Madagascar, serpent world contract and letters, hemipenis literature-snakes.
    - Misc Undated MS, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_69)
      bay 12, drawer 3
      Class family lists of Genera, AID vs time, crotalidae, dipsadidae, pythonidae, natricidae, lamprophildae, viperidae, Elaphe I, Miscellaneous notes 1996, scale reductions.
    - Misc Undated MS, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_70)
      natural history, venemous collaborators, National geographic (correspondence and articles), microdermatoglyphitics, slow evolving trees 1994, Nerodia Harteri.
    - Misc Undated MS, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_71)
      Taxonomy definitions, Genera format, scale reductions, miscellaneous notes.
    - Misc Correspondence, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_72)
      bay 12, drawer 4
      general correspondence and correspondence filed by last name.
    - Misc Correspondence, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_73)
      Johns Hopkins 1965-1968, Equinox xerox copy (encyclopedia), Acete publishing correspondence.
    - Misc Materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_74)
      bay 11, drawer 2
      Correspondence, reprints of articles, manuscripts, Dowling class 1997 tables.
    - Misc Materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_75)
      miscellaneous printouts, miscellaneous correspondence (emails), reprints of articles and publications.
    - Misc Materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_76)
      bay 9, drawer 2
      systemic herpatology illustrations, relic snakes, suborder serpentines, malagasian snakes.
  - Alphabetical files, circa 1960-2000
    This material is unprocessed. Files arranged alphabetically by last name of scientist. Originally, these materials were kept in Bays 4-9, drawers 2 and 3.
    Box ms059_files_9 - A-B
    Box ms059_files_10-10.1 - C
    Box ms059_files_11 - E-F
    Box ms059_files_12 - G
    Box ms059_files_13-13.1 - H
    Box ms059_files_14-14.1 - I-K
    Box ms059_files_15-18 - L-M
    Box ms059_files_19-20 - M-O
    Box ms059_files_22-25 - P-R
    Box ms059_files_26-29 - S-T
    - A-B, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_09)
      bay 4, drawer 2
    - B-C, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_10)
    - C, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_10.1)
    - D-F, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_11)
      bay 5, drawer 2
    - G, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_12)
      bay 5, drawer 3
    - H, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_13)
      bay 6, drawer 2
    - H, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_13.1)
    - I-K, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_14)
      bay 6, drawer 3
    - K, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_14.1)
    - L, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_15)
      bay 7, drawer 2
    - L-M, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_16)
    - M, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_17)
    - M, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_18)
    - N, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_19)
      bay 7, drawer 3
    - O, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_20)
    - P, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_22)
      bay 8, drawer 2
    - Q-R, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_23)
    - R-S, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_24)
    - S, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_25)
    - S, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_26)
      bay 8, drawer 3
    - T, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_27)
    - T-W, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_28)
    - W-Z, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_29)
  - Field Work
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_93)
      Field work materials.
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_94)
    - Misc materials, 1940-2009 (Box ms059_files_95)
- Journals
  - Alabama Heritage, 1993-2012 (Item 1)
    Number of Issues: 45; Content in box(es): 23
  - American Scientist, 2008-2010 (Item 2)
    Number of Issues: 9; Content in box(es): 23
  - American Zoologist, 1965-2001 (Item 3)
    Number of Issues: 75; Content in box(es): 17, 35, No box
  - Amphibia, 1956-1961 (Item 4)
    Number of Issues: 4; Content in box(es): No box
  - Amphibia-Reptilia, 1992-2007 (Item 5)
    Number of Issues: 63; Content in box(es): 2, 13, 31
  - British Herpetological Journal, 1990-1991 (Item 6)
    Number of Issues: 2; Content in box(es): 2
  - British Herpetological Society Bulletin, 1989-1990 (Item 7)
    Number of Issues: 6; Content in box(es): No box
  - British Herpetological Society Newsletter, 1974-1979 (Item 8)
    Number of Issues: 12; Content in box(es): 25
  - British Journal of Herpetology, 1948-1979 (Item 9)
    Number of Issues: 50; Content in box(es): 2, 25, No box
  - Bulletin of the the Chicago Herpetological Society, 2002-2013 (Item 10)
    Number of Issues: 125; Content in box(es): 29
  - Catalog of Amphibians and reptiles, ca. 2004 (Item 11)
    Number of Issues: 1; Content in box(es): 24
  - Chicago Herpetological Society Bulletin, 1988-2010 (Item 12)
    Number of Issues: 111; Content in box(es): 5
  - Chicago Herpetological Society Membership list, 1997 (Item 13)
    Number of Issues: 1; Content in box(es): 5
  - Contributions to American Herpetology, 1971-1973 (Item 14)
    Number of Issues: 6; Content in box(es): 2
  - Copeia, 1913-2013 (Item 15)
    Number of Issues: 494; Content in box(es): 7, 11, 20, 22, No box
  - Dopeia, 1969-1988 (Item 16)
  - Evolution, 1950-2010 (Item 17)
    Number of Issues: 349; Content in box(es): 7, 8, 19, 21, 28, 30, 37, 38
  - HERP New York Herpetological Society, 1968-1972 (Item 18)
    Number of Issues: 2; Content in box(es): 5
  - Herpetologica, 1936-2009 (Item 19)
    Number of Issues: 241; Content in box(es): 3, 4, 7, 9, 12, No Box
  - Herpetological Monographs, 1988-2009 (Item 20)
    Number of Issues: 19; Content in box(es): 2
  - Herpetological Review, 1968-2009 (Item 21)
    Number of Issues: 169; Content in box(es): 27, 31, 33, 34
  - HISS, 1973-1973 (Item 22)
    Number of Issues: 10; Content in box(es): 1
  - Journal of Herpetology, 1968-2009 (Item 23)
    Number of Issues: 146; Content in box(es): 15, 4, 14, No box
  - Journal of Vertebrate Paleontology, 1984-1994 (Item 24)
    Number of Issues: 42; Content in box(es): 10
  - Molecular biology and evolution, 1983-2000 (Item 25)
    Number of Issues: 102; Content in box(es): 1, 18, 27
  - Principles of Biology (microfilm), 1976-1976 (Item 26)
    Number of Issues: ~50; Content in box(es): No box
  - Quarterly Review of Biology, 1993-2008 (Item 27)
    Number of Issues: 62; Content in box(es): 6
  - Reptile and Amphibian Hobbyist, 1999-2001 (Item 28)
    Number of Issues: 29; Content in box(es): 26
  - Reptile and Amphibian Magazine, 1993-1997 (Item 29)
    Number of Issues: 23; Content in box(es): 23, 26
  - Reptilia, 1955-1965 (Item 30)
    Number of Issues: 9; Content in box(es): No box
  - Salamandra, 1965-1976 (Item 31)
    Number of Issues: 24; Content in box(es): 25, No box
  - Smithsonian herpetological bulletins and indexes various, 1968-1999 (Item 32)
    Number of Issues: 32; Content in box(es): No box
  - Smithsonian Herpetological Information Service, 1982-2000 (Item 33)
    Number of Issues: 11; Content in box(es): 5
  - Society of Vertebrate Paleontology News bulletin, 1989-1995 (Item 34)
    Number of Issues: 10; Content in box(es): 10
  - Southeastern Biology, 2002-2007 (Item 35)
    Number of Issues: 17; Content in box(es): 13
  - Systematic Biology, 1992-2005 (Item 36)
    Number of Issues: 59; Content in box(es): 32, 33, 35, 39
  - Systematic Zoology, 1949-1991 (Item 37)
    Number of Issues: 152; Content in box(es): 16, 20, 32, 35, 39
  - The Japanese Journal of Herpetology, 1971-1985 (Item 38)
    Number of Issues: 22; Content in box(es): 16
  - The Snake, 1969-1998 (Item 39)
    Number of Issues: 50; Content in box(es): 16
  - Various single issues and bulletins, 1883-2000 (Item 40)
    Number of Issues: 18; Content in box(es): No box
  - Vivarium, 1993-1998 (Item 41)
    Number of Issues: 27; Content in box(es): 26